An Inventory of the Abraham D. Sofaer Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Miscellany (Box 123)
  - 2003-2004. (Folder 123: 1-2)
    Includes 1 photographic print depicting Steve and Sabrina Forbes and others
  - 2004 (Folder 123: 3)
  - 2004-2005 (Folder 124: 1)
    Includes 1 performing arts CD, 2006
  - 2006. (Folder 125: 1)
    Includes 2 photographic prints depicting Abraham Sofaer, George Shultz and other unidentified individuals
- List of Hoover Institution memorabilia, undated (Folder 126: 1)
- International Cooperation to Combat Cyber Crime and Terrorism, conference proceedings, Hoover Institution, Stanford University, California, 1999 (Folder 126: 2)
- Books presented to Abraham Sofaer
  - 1985-1988 (Folder 126: 3)
  - 1993-2003 (Folder 126: 4)
  - 2000-2007 (Folder 127: 1-2)
- Briefing book, 1970-1989 (Folder 127: 3)
- Miscellany, 2007. (Folder 127: 4)
  Includes clipping and speech by George P. Shultz
- Miscellany, 1984-2007. (Folder 128: 1)
  Includes book by other, journal, leaflets, notes, printed matter, and speech by George P. Shultz and his letter to Abraham Sofaer
- Memorabilia – Plaque, poster of American Jewish Historical Society and a Waterford crystal ball, undated (Folder 128: 2)
- Biological and Chemical Weapons Conference, Hoover Institution, Stanford University, California, 1998. (Box 129: 1)
  Includes 11 audio cassettes
- Taba project, 1988-1996 (Folder 130: 1)
- Ariel Sharon – Middle East, 1989-2004 (Folder 130: 2)
- Correspondence – Hughes Hubbard and Reed, 1990-2002 (Folder 130: 3)
- Legal advisor, 1985-1990 (Folder 131: 1)
- Iranian airbus, 1989 (Folder 131: 2)
- Iran Small Claims Settlement, 1990 (Folder 131: 3)
- American Embassy – Baghdad, 1985-2005 (Folder 131: 4)
- Legal Advisor documents, 1986-1990 (Folder 131: 5)
- Letelier claim, 1989 (Folder 131: 6)
- International Court of Justice (ICJ), 1989-1990 (Folder 131: 7)
- Prewitt Enterprises, Inc. vs. OPEC, 1982-2004 (Folder 131: 8)
- Correspondence. (Box 132)
  Includes related materials
  - Pollard, 1992-2002 (Folder 132: 1)
  - Chemonics, 2006 (Folder 132: 2)
  - Miscellany, 1998-2006 (Folder 132: 3)
  - Haim Harel, 1999 (Folder 132: 4)
  - Joel Hyatt and Robert L. Nelson, Jr., 1999-2000 (Folder 132: 5)
  - Sarah Isgur, 1999 (Folder 132: 6)
  - Ariel Levite, 2000 (Folder 132: 7)
  - John McGinnis, 1999-2001 (Folder 132: 8)
  - Eival Gilady, 2000 (Folder 132: 9)
  - Boris Feldman, 2001 (Folder 132: 10)
  - Edward G. Abington, Jr., 1999 (Folder 132: 11)
  - Ian C. Ballon, 2001 (Folder 132: 12)
  - David W. Ogden, 1999 (Folder 132: 13)
  - Robert L. Nelson, Jr., 1999 (Folder 132: 14)
  - Biological and Chemical Weapons Conference, Hoover Institution, Stanford University, California, 1998 (Folder 132: 15)
  - Miscellany including a framed wooden plaque, 2004 (Folder 132: 16)
- Legal records relating to various cases, 1995-1999 (Folder 133: 1-3)
- Israel sewage and Yarqon river, 1999-2004 (Folder 133: 4)
- 1 CD, undated (Folder 133: 5)
- Legal records relating to various cases, 1995-2000 (Folder 134: 1-3)
- Audio-Visual materials (Box 135)
  - VHS video cassettes
    - Untitled, undated
    - Castles Made of Sand, 2004
    - Chat with Abraham Sofaer of Hoover on Current Affairs, 2004
    - Chat with Abraham Sofaer of Hoover Institute, 2004 (2 video cassettes), undated
    - Discussion about Chemical Warfare, 2002
    - Discussion with Abraham Sofaer of the Hoover Institution, undated
    - Iraq
      - Speaks on Iraq, 2003-2004 and undated
        (3 video cassettes)
      - Focus Segment on Possible War with Iraq, 2002
      - Speech on Possible Iraq War, 2002
      - On Looming Iraq War, undated (Box 136)
      - On Iraq Conflict, 2003
      - Speech on Iraqi Handover, 2004
    - Middle East, undated
    - On Middle East Developments, 2003
    - Military Tribunal Discussion, 2002
    - On New Gulf War, 2003
    - On New UN Resolution, 2003
    - Possible Terrorist Attacks, 2002
    - On State Assassination, 2003
    - Report from the Security Conference at Hoover Institution
    - Terrorism Expert Abraham Sofaer of the Hoover Institution, undated
    - The Thin Blue Line: United Nations Peacekeeping with Stephen Stedman, undated (Box 137)
    - The War on Bugs: Bioterrorism, undated
  - Compact disks
    - Michael Krasny Forum, undated
    - Chat with Abraham Sofaer of Hoover Institution, KQED-Forum, 2004
    - Forum, Michael Krasny, 2003
    - Forum on Iraq, undated
    - KQED – Public Radio, undated
    - Speaks on Current Terrorism Scenario, KGO Pete Wilson Program, 2004
    - Speaks on the Future of Iraq, KQED –Forum, 2004
  - Audio cassettes
    - Necessity of Preemption - Copy of talk, Stauffer Auditorium, Hoover Institution, 2002
    - The War on Terrorism, 2002
- Boxes closed during the lifetime of Abraham D. Sofaer (Box 138-139)
- Memorabilia - Poster, undated; 1 framed plaque of "The War Powers: Theory and Practice," Arizona State University, 2000; and a book by Angus Gavin, 1996 (Box 140)
- History – Primary source documents relating to early American History, 2006 (Folder 141: 1)
- Legal records – Hamdi vs. Donald Rumsfeld, 2006 (Folder 141: 2)
- Balli Klockner (Germany)vs. Jindal Iron and Steel Co. Ltd. (India), 2006 (Folder 141: 3)
- Dana Corporation vs. Certain Underwriters at Lloyd's London, Center for Public Resources Wellington Agreement, 2002 (Folder 141: 4)
- Revolution – The Legal Dimension, Abbott Laboratories, Inc., ICC International Court of Arbitration, 2005-2007 (Folder 141: 5)
- JDS Uniphase (JDSU), 2007. (Folder 141: 6)
  Advice
- Miscellany, 2000-2006. (Folder 141: 7)
  Clipping about laws of war, security, printed matter, issue of presidential power
- John Yoo, 2006. (Folder 142: 1)
  Articles. Includes articles by others
- Legal Records and research materials.
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) vs. National Security Agency (NSA), 2006. (Folder 142: 2-3)
  - Hamdan vs. Rumsfeld, 2006 (Folder 142: 4)
  - War powers, 2006. (Folder 142: 5)
    Articles
  - Chevron USA, Inc. and Valley Pines Associates vs. Combustion Engineering, Inc., 2006 (Folder 143: 1)
  - Chemical Overseas vs. Republic of Uruguay – International Chamber of Commerce, 2003-2004 (Folder 143: 2)
  - CGEA ONYX vs. Waster Management, Inc. (U.S.A.) – International Court of Arbitration, 2002 (Folder 143: 3)
  - Braniff International Airlines, Inc., 1995-2003 (Folder 143: 4)
  - Pioneer Natural Resources USA, Inc., 2005 (Folder 143: 5)
  - Alliance of Automobile Manufacturers and the Association of International Automobile Manufacturers, 2006. (Folder 143: 6)
    Abraham is invited to provide confidential and privileged advice in a moot court
  - Lloyd's vs. Amchem Products, Inc., 2006 (Folder 144: 1)
  - Fireman's Fund and CAN vs, Thorpe Insulation Co., CPR Institute for Dispute Resolution, 2001-2003 (Folder 144: 2)
  - CDR Créances S. A., as successor to Société de Banque Occidentale vs. Euro-American Lodging Corporation, 1990-2006 (Folder 144: 3)
  - Merrill Lynch vs. Allegheny Energy, 2005 (Folder 144: 4)
  - Zimmer vs. Niznick, 2005-2006 (Folder 144: 5)
  - Lockheed Martin Corporation vs. Lloyds, 2003 (Folder 144: 6)
  - JTS Communities, Inc. and Clarendon National Insurance Company, 2004 (Folder 144: 7)
  - Heerema Marine Contractors Nederland BV vs. ABB/Grootint B.V. Joint Venture, 2005 (Folder 144: 8)
  - Gartmore vs. Berkshire Hathaway, 2006-2007 (Folder 144: 9)
  - Asichem Trading (S) Pte Limited vs.Tricon Energy Ltd., 2005-2006 (Folder 144: 10)
  - Dana Corporation vs. Lloyds, London, 2004 (Folder 144: 11)
  - Daicel Chemical Industries Ltd. Vs. OEA, Inc., International Chamber of Commerce, 2002-2005 (Folder 144: 12)
- Reports to President's Commission on Critical Infrastructure Protection, 1997 (Box 145)
  - The Regulatory Landscape: Overview of the Impacts of Regulatory Agency Practices on Critical Infrastructure Protection (Folder 145: 1)
  - Legal Foundations: Studies and Conclusions. Report to 1 of 12 (Folder 145: 2)
  - Legal Authorities Database: A Legal Foundations Study. Report 4 of 12 (Folder 145: 3)
  - Major Federal legislation: A Legal Foundations Study. Report 6 of 12 (Folder 145: 4)
  - Adequacy of Criminal Law and Procedure (Physical): A Legal Foundations Study. Report 8 of 12 (Folder 145: 5)
  - Privacy Laws and the Employer-Employee Relationship: A Legal Foundations Study. Report 9 of 12 (Folder 145: 6)
  - Legal Impediments to Information Sharing: A Legal Foundations Study. Report 10 of 12 (Folder 145: 7)
  - Federal Government Model Performance: A Legal Foundations Study. Report 11 of 12 (Folder 145: 8)
  - Approaches to Cyber Intrusion Response: A Legal Foundations Study. Report 12 of 12 (Folder 145: 9)
- "Cyberspace Self-Governance: A Skeptical View from Liberal Democratic Theory," Neil Weinstock Netanel, California Law Review, 2000 March. (Folder 145: 10)
- Legal Records and research materials.
  - World Omni Financial Corporation vs. ACE Capital Re Overseas Ltd., 2004 (Folder 145: 11)
  - BNP Paribus (France) vs. AVIS Group Holdings, Inc. and VMS (Bermuda) Holdings Ltd., 2004 (Folder 145: 12)
- Miscellany, undated (Folder 145: 13)
- Drafts and copies of articles, minutes of meetings, presentation to Stanford Discriminate Force Project and related materials, 1996-2001 (Folder 146: 1)
- Cyber Crime Conference – Legal documents, 1999 (Folder 146: 2)
- The Case for Israel by Alan Dershowitz, 2003 (Folder 147: 1)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 2007 (Folder 147: 2)
- Books by others, 1999-2007 (Folder 148: 1)
- Articles, clippings, and printed matter, 1996 (Folder 148: 2)
- Correspondence with George P. Shultz, memoranda for the Bush-Quayle Committee, and article by Abraham Sofaer, 1988-1995 (Folder 148: 3)
- Article about Ariel Sharon, 1998. (Folder 148: 4)
  In Hebrew
- Correspondence with Peter Tarnoff, 1991 (Folder 148: 5)
- Red Mountain Finance, Inc. vs. Democratic Republic of Congo and Central Bank of Congo, 1999-2000. (Folder 148: 6)
  Legal records
- Introduction of Frederick Frank and Alan M. Dershowitz by Abraham Sofaer, 2007 (Folder 148: 7)
- Books by others including one about Hoover Dam Documents, 1948-2007 (Box 149)
- Oversize Jury notes relating to Ariel Sharon vs. Time case, undated (Box 150)
- Memorabilia and photographs, undated (Box 151)
  - Gavel, seal of the Supreme Court of the United Stated, and paperweight with the image of Herbert Hoover
  - 3 photographs depicting Abraham Sofaer with Warren Christopher and George Shultz and other unidentified individuals, undated
- General Electric case papers, 1976 (Folder 152)
  SEE ALSO Box 34